Guide to the William Wilson papers, 1978-1997 MS2033
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
William Wilson papers
1978-1997
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Wilson, William
MS2033
1.5 Linear Feet
The William Wilson papers consists materials such as buttons, t-shirts, and printed material including programs for entertainment events and fundraisers. The material dates from 1978-97. Many of this material is from events that Mr. Williams attended. Many of the items are autographed by local and national celebrities, including former DC Council member Polly Shackleton and Congressman Barney Frank. Most of the t-shirts and buttons have messages related to Gay pride, political activism, and the fight against AIDS.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
William Wilson donated the collection to the Gelman Library in 1998.
Biographical Note
Mr. Wilson, a resident of the District from 1972-97, collected a number of t-shirts, political buttons, and programs relating to the Gay and Lesbian culture of the city.
Collection Scope and Content
The William Wilson papers consists materials such as buttons, t-shirts, and printed material including programs for entertainment events and fundraisers. The material dates from 1978-97. Many of this material is from events that Mr. Williams attended. Many of the items are autographed by local and national celebrities, including former DC Council member Polly Shackleton and Congressman Barney Frank. Most of the t-shirts and buttons have messages related to Gay pride, political activism, and the fight against AIDS.
Collection Organization
Organized into three series: Printed materials, T-shirts, and Buttons.
Collection note
Formerly Ephemera Collection 11
Lesbians -- Washington (D.C.); Gays; Gay men -- Washington (D.C.); Washington (D.C.); AIDS (Disease); Shackleton, Polly; Whitman-Walker Clinic; Wilson, William; National AIDS Network (U.S.); Matlovich, Leonard; Human Rights Campaign (U.S.); Gay Men's Chorus of Washington, DC; Frank, Barney
- Printed material, 1983-1996; MS2033 Series 1; 0.5 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains programs, tickets, a postcard, and a newsletter. The material covers the dates 1983-96. All of this material relates to the activities of the Gay and Lesbian community in Washington, D.C. Many of these items are autographed.
  - Program -- "A Gay Yuletide" - Joint Holiday Concert with The D.C. Area Feminist Chorus, D.C.'s Different Drummers, The Gay Men's Chorus of Washington, D.C. and Carl Barnwell at the Great Casavant Organ. -- Autographed- "Best Wishes, Bill! Jim Richardson." "Caroline Foty." "Gerry Walker.", 1983 December 10 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
  - Program -- "Made in America" - Gay Men's Chorus of Washington, D.C. -- Autographed - "To Bill Best Wishes, James Adler.", 1984 March 17-24 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Ticket -- "The Michael Greer Show." -- Autographed - "Bill! Love you! No merde! Michael Greer.", 1985 February 28 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Newsletter -- Gertrude Stein Democratic Club., 1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Program -- Gertrude Stein Democratic Club 10th Anniversary Banquet. -- Autographed - "Bill - Thanks for being there. Steve Smith." "Best wishes from Polly Shackleton." "Thanks for supporting so many good causes Barney Frank." "With best wishes Effi Barry.", 1986 May 09 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Program -- "As Is" -- Autographed - "For Bill From William M. Hoffman.", 1986 July 29 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Program -- "Silverbelle" - An Evening with Patti LaBelle. -- Autographed - "With Best Wishes, Effi Barry.", 1987 March 28 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Program - Americans Who Care, A Project of the National AIDS Network., 1987 October 09 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Program -- "Americans Who Care: Volunteers Working in the Battle Against AIDS." -- Autographed - "For Bill - Love, Morgan Fairchild." "To Bill Nice to Meet You Joel Brooks." "To Bill Thank you Love Lorna Luft.", 1987 October (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Program and News clipping -- Funeral of Leonard Matlovich., 1988 June (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Program -- "Whitman-Walker Clinic Honors Its Volunteers" - "Extraordinary People". -- Autographed - "To Bill - Very Best! Henry Tenebaum." "To Bill: With very warm regards. AS Fauci, MD.", 1988 November 19 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Program -- "Gay and Lesbian Inaugural Celebration.", 1993 January 18-20 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Program -- "Let Freedom Ring" - Gertrude Stein Democratic Club Banquet. -- Autographed - "Happy to be here - Roberta Achtenberg.", 1993 September 11 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Postcard -- AIDSWALK '95 - Photograph of Tipper Gore., 1995 September 23 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Program -- Human Rights Campaign - Washington D.C. Gala.-- Autographed - "Bill Best Wishes, Steve Gunderson.", 1995 November 11 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Program -- "Campaign Crazy" - Gay Men's Chorus of Washington, D.C. -- Autographed - "Bill, darling, Hope I've got your VOTE!!! Love, Mrs Foggybottom.", 1996 March 29-30 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- T-shirts, 1983-1997; MS2033 Series 2; 0.5 Linear feet
  This series contains t-shirts related to the activities of the Gay and Lesbian community in Washington, D.C. The materials cover the dates 1983-97.
  - Tee-shirt -- Black; medium. -- "National AIDS Vigil October 8, 1983 Washington, D.C.", 1983 October 08 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Tee-shirt -- Black; silk screened in pink, purple and green; large. -- flamingos with lambdas as legs wading in reflecting pool., 1986 June 22 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Tee-shirt -- Blue; pink heart; extra-large. -- "Celebrate Volunteers Whitman-Walker Clinic 1986" (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Tee-shirt -- Green; pink and white printing; extra-large. -- "March on Washington; We're Not Going Back; National March on Washington for Lesbian and Gay Rights October 11, 1987", 1987 October 11 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Tee-shirt -- Blue; silk screened in pink and black; capitol dome with pink triangles; large. -- "We, the people Proud, United, Strong", 1987 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Tee-shirt -- White; extra-large. -- "The Next Step AIDSWALK Washington 88 Sunday May 15, 1988", 1988 May 15 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Tee-shirt -- White; silk screened in red and grey; red lambdas above red bars, symbolic of the DC flag; large, 1988 June 19 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Tee-shirt -- White; purple and black printing; image of Jesse Jackson; extra-large. -- "Jesse Jackson '88 It's Time For a Change", 1988 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Tee-shirt -- White; black printing; black fist holding pen, paint brush; large. -- "Freedom for the Creative Mind". Back -"Mapplethorpe Protest at the Corcoran Gallery of Art 9 pm June 30, 1989", 1989 June 30 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Tee-shirt -- White; black printing. -- "Let's All Come Together Banneker Field NW Saturday, May 25, 1991 Black Lesbian & Gay Pride Day Inc.", 1991 May 25 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Tee-shirt -- White; multi-colored; male and female figures raising rainbow flag; extra-large. -- "Pride=Power Lesbian and Gay Pride Day Washington, D.C. June 21, 1992", 1992 June 21 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Tee-shirt -- Red; black printing; ex-large. -- "Black Lesbian & Gay Pride Day Pride=Power Washington, D.C.", 1992 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Tee-shirt -- Grey; blue printing; extra-large. -- "Gay and Lesbian Voters for Clinton/Gore Human Rights Campaign Fund", 1992 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Tee-shirt -- White; silk screened in blue, pink, and orange; extra-large. -- "The 1993 March on Washington for Lesbian, Gay and Bi Equal Rights and Liberation April 25", 1993 April 25 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Tee-shirt -- White; silk screened in white, red, yellow, and green; extra-large. -- "Visibility, the Key to Pride '95 Black Pride Weekend May 26-28 Washington, D.C.", 1995 May 26-28 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Tee-shirt -- White; silk screened in blue, purple and black; extra-large. --"Come Out Proud! 20 years of Pride Lesbian and Gay Freedom Festival June 11-18, 1995 Washington, D.C.", 1995 June 11-18 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Tee-shirt -- Blue printing; extra-large. -- "Clinton Gore '96" on pink triangle., 1996 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Tee-shirt -- Purple; silk screened in black, green, red and yellow; extra-large. -- "Black Pride '97 Proud Sisters & Brothers Washington, D.C.", 1997 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Tee-shirt -- Purple; silk screened in black, green, red and yellow; extra-large. -- "Black Pride '97 Proud Sisters & Brothers Washington, D.C.", 1997 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Tee-shirt -- Black; pink and white printing; extra-large. -- "Lift the Ban NOW (National Organization for Women)", undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Tee-shirt -- Blue printing; extra-large. -- "SHARE Study Help Aids Research Effort", undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Buttons, 1978-1996; MS2033 Series 3; 0.5 Linear feet
  This series contains buttons related to the activies of the Gay and Lesbian community in Washington, D.C. The material covers the dates 1978-96.
  - Political button -- "Lesbian and Gay Voters for Mayor Barry", 1978 (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Gay and lesbian pride button -- "Washington, D.C. Lesbian & Gay Pride '83", 1983 (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 3, Box 2)
  - Political button -- "Gays for Mondale", 1984 (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Political button -- "Vote Mondale for President Maccubbin for Delegate", 1984 (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Political button -- "Vote Democratic the ass you save might be your own", 1984 (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Gay and lesbian pride button -- "Pride Week Washington, D.C. "We the People..." Proud, United, Strong 1987" (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Aidswalk button -- "Ask me about THE NEXT STEP", 1987 June 28 (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Political button -- "Lesbian and Gays for Jackson '88 Lavender Stripe", 1988 (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Gay and lesbian pride button -- "Washington D.C. June 23, 1991 Together in Pride '91", 1991 June 02 (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Gay and lesbian pride button -- "Black Lesbian & Gay Pride Day '92 Pride=Power Washington, D.C. May 22-24", 1992 May 22-24 (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Gay and lesbian pride button -- "Pride=Power Lesbian & Gay Pride Day Washington, D.C. June 21, 1992", 1992 June 21 (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Aidswalk button -- "Heart & Soles Aidswalk Washington SATURDAY September 26 1992", 1992 September 26 (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Political button -- "Bill Clinton for President", 1992 (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Gay and lesbian pride button -- "Keep in Stride with Black Pride Black Lesbian and Gay Pride Weekend '94 May 27-30 Washington, D.C.", 1994 May 27-30 (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Gay and lesbian pride button -- "Come Out Proud" "20 Years of Pride", "Lesbian & Gay FREEDOM FESTIVAL June 11-18, 1995 Washington, D.C.", 1995 June 11-18 (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Aidswalk button -- "Aidswalk Washington Sat. Sept 23 '95 A Pledgewalk Sponsored by Whitman-Walker Clinic 202-332-WALK", 1995 November 23 (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Gay and lesbian pride button -- Black on yellow. "Black Pride Day '95 5th Anniversary Washington, D.C.", 1995 (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Gay and lesbian pride button -- Same as above except full color design on white background., 1995 (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Political button -- "Gays and Lesbians for Clinton Gore 96", 1996 (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Political button -- "Chorlton", undated (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Political button -- "I Support Bill 6-343", undated (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Aidswalk button -- "PLEDGE ME!", undated (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Political button -- "Zais Ward 2", undated (Box SHARED Box 17, Box 4, Folder 10)